adaa.org 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy | Anxiety and Depression Association of America, ADAA

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors. This policy sets out how we will treat your personal information. This privacy policy applies to the websites at ADAA.org, and any other ADAA-related site featuring a link to this privacy policy, and any mobile applications featuring a link to this privacy policy which are owned and/or operated by ADAA. By using our site or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the collection, processing, disclosure, and other use of your personal information as described in this privacy policy.

We may change this privacy policy from time to time by updating this page. We will not explicitly inform users of updates and recommend you review this page frequently so that you are aware of our latest policy. Your continued use of our site and any of our services constitutes your continued acceptance of our then-current privacy policy. If you do not grant this consent, you are not permitted to use our site.

### **What Information Do We Collect?**

We collect, store and use the following kinds of personal information as needed to facilitate and improve the services and information we provide:

  * Information about your computer and about your visits to and use of ADAA's website. For example, we may collect IP addresses, click-stream data, length of session, and other information related to your use of our site for purposes of system administration, to improve our site, to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, and/or other internal uses related to our site.
  * Information that you provide to us for the purpose of joining our organization, subscribing to our services, email notifications and/or newsletters, including name, email address, phone number, mailing address and/or credit card number, and also including any information we may collect from you off-line (such as personal information you have sent us by postal mail or provided in person at an event). To make your experiences on our site and with us more convenient, we gather this information directly from you.

### **Analytics Tools**

Our site uses standard technology called “cookies,” which are small data files that are transferred to your hard drive when your browser settings permit the acceptance of cookies. We or our third-party advertisers or service providers may also use web beacons or similar technologies. Cookies automatically identify your web browser whenever you visit our site, and save your user ID, preferences and other information related to your use of our site. By tracking how and when you use or site, cookies help us determine which features and content are most important to our visitors. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on our site. Cookies may also allow us to display advertising which may of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, you generally can turn off cookies in your browser; however, some areas of the site may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. Most browsers allow you to reject all cookies, while some browsers allow you to reject just third-party cookies.

We may use “Google Analytics” or similar tools or services to collect information such as how often users visit our site, what pages they visit when they do, and what other sites they used prior to visiting our site. We use the information we obtain from Google Analytics and similar services to improve our website and tailor it to the needs of our users. Google Analytics may collect the IP address assigned to you on the date you access our site, as well as your gender, age, interest categories, and other information to the extent it is available to Google Analytics. Google’s use of information collected by Google Analytics is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to our site by disabling cookies on your browser.

### **How is the Information Used?**

We use the personally-identifiable information for the specific purpose it was provided (for example, to process a membership, registration, product order, etc.).  We may also use your information to analyze use of our services, improve and customize our offerings, send our users email reminders, and to provide you other information that we believe may interest you. 

Specifically, we may use your personal information:

  * To provide member related services
  * To deliver services, such as educational programs, information or newsletters you request or purchase
  * To send marketing communications relating to our organization which we think may be of interest to you by email or similar technology (you can inform us at any time if you no longer require marketing communications)
  * To alert you to special offers, updated information and other new services from ADAA, other third parties, or to forward promotional materials
  * To process your order and, if necessary, to contact you regarding the status of your order
  * To fulfill the terms of a promotion
  * To ensure the ADAA website is relevant to your needs
  * To help us create and publish content most relevant to you
  * To request your feedback about your experience with ADAA
  * To notify you about a material change to this privacy policy
  * To answer inquiries, content submissions and complaints made by or about you relating to the website

When you register for a conference or other event, the information you will provide will be used for purposes related to that event. For example, your name, job title, credentials, and/or company name and other information collected may be included in a list of conference attendees and your name and contact information may be provided to event sponsors and exhibitors who wish to notify you about event activities and their products and services.

### **Protecting your Privacy**

We keep all information you provide confidential to ADAA, with the exception of event registration information as provided above. As part of our commitment to ensuring the privacy of our users, we do not sell or exchange names or any other personally identifiable information about our users and members with, for example, mass marketers. We keep confidential any personal information entered during registration, although we may share aggregate information about website usage and traffic patterns, stripped of any personally identifiable information, to third parties to comply with various reporting obligations and for business or marketing purposes. We may also share limited personally identifiable information with third parties on a confidential basis to enable a third party to perform certain tasks, such as maintain an e-mail list or send e-mail alerts and newsletters, on our behalf. When we do so, we use reasonable efforts to assure that they comply with our privacy policy and applicable laws.

### **Mailing Lists and Newsletters**

We use your personal information to send you e-newsletters and program updates. These include helpful resources, articles, stories from our communities, fundraising initiatives, new webinars, blog posts and treatment/research news from the ADAA professional community. You may subscribe to email and newsletter lists in various places on our site and, in some cases,  you will be subscribed to email lists based on other activities, such as membership or event registration. 

We may use a third-party provider to deliver our email content. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter and to improve on our communications marketing approaches to better suit your needs.

For more information on our current third-party service provider, please see [Constant Contact's privacy notice](https://www.constantcontact.com/legal/privacy-statement). Your email address will be stored in Constant Contact's database for as long as we continue to use their services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You are legally entitled to inform us at any time if you no longer wish to receive these newsletters and may do so by emailing us at [information@adaa.org ](mailto:information@adaa.org)or you may [unsubscribe](https://www.constantcontact.com/legal/privacy-statement#choice) yourself). We do not rent or trade email lists with other organizations and businesses. 

We will not, without your expressed consent, provide your personal information to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing.

### **Disclosures**

We may disclose information about you to any of our employees, officers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes as set out in this privacy policy.

In addition, we may disclose your personal information:

  * To the extent that we are required to do so by law, regulation, rule or court order;
  * Pursuant to requests from governmental, regulatory or administrative agencies or law enforcement authorities;
  * To prevent, investigate, identify persons or organizations potentially involved in, or take any action regarding suspected fraud, potential illegal activity, or activity we believe may expose us to legal liability; and/or
  * In situations which we believe to be emergencies involving potential threats to physical safety of any person if we believe that your information in any way relates to that threat.

Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties. In accordance with California law, residents of California may obtain a list of the kinds of personally-identifiable information we have disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, and the names and addresses of all third parties that received such information from us for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, by writing to us at the address below.

### **Security of your Personal Information**

We have implemented reasonable technical and organizational security measures to safeguard your personal information and prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and accordingly, we cannot guarantee the security of your data or that your data will always remain secure. Transactions on our site are primarily protected by encryption software and we may use other technologies in the future to protect your information.

You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will never ask you for your password (except when you log into the professional member community and online community via this website).

### **Privacy of Minors**

Our services are not intended for use by minors. We do not knowingly collect personally-identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under age 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete the child’s personal information (except as may be necessary for legal compliance) and remove the child from any mailing lists.

### **Release and Limitation of Liability**

By providing us with any personally-identifiable information, you expressly and unconditionally release and hold harmless ADAA and its respective shareholders, owners, members, directors, officers, employees and agents from any and all liability for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your information. In addition, while we take reasonable steps to prevent third party companies from making unauthorized use of your personal information, we cannot be held liable for any injuries, loss or damage of any kind arising from or in connection with the use and/or misuse of your collected personally-identifiable information by those third parties.

### **Your Rights**

You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you. Provision of such information will be subject to the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity.

You may instruct us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes by email at any time.  You are entitled to view, update, amend, or delete your personal information that we hold. Email your request to us at [information@adaa.org](mailto:information@adaa.org).

### **EU User Consent and Data Subjects**

We are headquartered in the United States. Your personal information may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to our affiliates, partners, merchants, or service providers who are located worldwide. If you are visiting our site from outside the United States, be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located, and our central database is operated. By using our site, you consent to any transfer of this information.

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), the Data Controller is the Anxiety and Depression Association of America in Maryland, USA with a registered address at 8701 Georgia Avenue, Suite 412, Silver Spring, MD 20910.

Our Deputy Executive Director is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this policy for the purposes of the GDPR. If you have any questions or concerns about this policy, or to exercise your rights as listed below, please contact us by phone at 240-485-1016, by sending an email to [information@adaa.org](mailto:information@adaa.org) or by postal mail to ADAA, 8701 Georgia Avenue, Suite 412, Silver Spring, MD 20910.

Any EU user not consenting to such uses of data and cookies by ADAA should not use this website.

_FOR EUROPEAN USERS ONLY_ : You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your personal data) if we intend to such information for marketing purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. Under European data protection law, in certain circumstances, you have the right to:

·         **Request access to your personal data**. You may have the right to request access to any personal data we hold about you as well as related information, including the purposes for processing the personal data, the recipients or categories of recipients with whom the personal data has been shared, where possible, the period for which the personal data will be stored, the source of the personal data, and the existence of any automated decision making.

·         **Request correction of your personal data**. You may have the right to obtain without undue delay the rectification of any inaccurate personal data we hold about you.

·         **Request erasure of your personal data.**  You may have the right to request that personal data held about you is deleted.

·         **Object to processing of your personal data.**  You may have the right to prevent or restrict processing of your personal data.

·         **Request restriction of processing your personal data; Request transfer of your personal data.** You may have the right to request transfer of personal data directly to a third party where this is technically feasible.

·         **Withdraw your consent**

In addition, where you believe that ADAA has not complied with its obligations under this privacy policy or European law, you have the right to make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority, such as the UK Information Commissioner’s Office.

### **Data Breaches**

We will report any unlawful data breach of this website's database or the database(s) of any of our third-party data processors to any and all relevant persons and authorities.

### **Third Party Websites**

The website contains links to third party websites which are beyond our control. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third party websites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these third-party websites prior to any use.

### This policy was updated on May 25, 2018.
